# GABRIEL MARIO ANTAPUTRA

Mobile: 85993730 Email: <a href="mailto:gabriel.mario.antaputra@gmail.com">gmail.com</a> https://github.com/thegrimbee https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriel-antaputra-658069222/

## SUMMARY

Computer Science student at National University of Singapore with a strong academic foundation and practical experience in Al development, software engineering, and data analytics. Proven ability in these fields and is willing to work hard to improve and learn!

#### **KEY PROJECTS**

### Horus (Self initiated)

- Co-created a desktop application to identify harmful terms of applications since majority of users do not read terms of service agreements, achieving more than 80% accuracy on untrained data despite having limited training data
- Gained practical experience of desktop application development with Electron JS, as well as Al development with Python (pandas, PyTorch, NLTK, spacy) and HuggingFace (MiniLM)

### MuhamMart (Self initiated)

- Co-developed a mini mart web application for Muhammadiyah Welfare Home, supporting it's 80+ residents with various features including product requests and user management
- Gained valuable experience of developing with React JS and Firebase, as well as UI design using Material-UI

## VirtualKey (Self initiated)

- Developed an android authenticator with a fun twist', to authenticate, users need to twist their phone similar to an
  actual key opening a lock, with more than half of users surveyed finding twisting satisfactory
- Gained practical experience of android development with React Native (TypeScript) as well as API development using Python's FastAPI

### RH Job Autofill (Raffles Hall Project)

- Co-developed a web extension to help auto fill information for job applications, particularly extracting information from job application pages to find job descriptions, speeding up job application by more than 100%
- Gained practical experience of OpenAl API, API testing with Postman, as well as frontend development with JS, HTML, and CSS

#### Rzone 3.0 (Raffles Hall Project)

- Co-developed Raffles Hall's web application for CCA management, from 2.0 (PHP) to 3.0 (React JS)
- Gained practical experience of implementing frontend with React JS and Chakra UI, as well as database management with MySQL

## **EDUCATION**

## **National University of Singapore**

Aug 2023 - Present

Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

GPA: 4.89

Second major in Data Analytics, specialisation in software engineering and Al

Dean's List for AY24/25 Semester 1

Relevant Coursework: CS2102 Database Systems (A), CS2109S Introduction to AI and Machine Learning (A), CS2040S Data Structure and Algorithms (A+), CS2105 Introduction to Computer Networks (A+), CS2100 Computer Organisation (A+)

## **Anglo-Chinese Junior College**

Jan 2021 - Dec 2022

GCE A Levels

88.75 RP (H2 Further Mathematics, H2 Mathematics, H2 Computing, H1 Economics President of Mathematics and Computing Club, Vice President of Technology Council Co-founded Peer Support Group, a group to help academically struggling students

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Logiscool (Singapore), Holiday Camp Trainer

Dec 2024 - Dec 2024

Taught young students about Minecraft redstone logic, video production, and block programming

### National University of Singapore (Singapore), Teaching Assistant

Aug 2024 - Nov 2024

 Tutored studio sessions in CS1101S Programming Methodology and grade student's work, receiving 100% positive reviews from students

### The Learning Lab (Singapore), Mathematics Teacher Intern

Dec 2023 - Jan 2024

Taught P5-S4 students, including Gifted Education Programme

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Technical Skills: Object Oriented Programming, SQL Database Management (Postgresql, MySQL), NoSQL Database Management (MongoDB, Firebase), Al Development, Data Analytics (R and Python), Web Scraping, Android Application Development (React Native and Kotlin), Desktop Application Development, REST API Development, Unit testing, API testing, MS Office (Excel, Word, Powerpoint), Web Development (React JS), Matlab, Material-UI
- Languages: English (Professional Working), Indonesian (Native), Malay (Intermediate)
- Awards: National Olympiad of Informatics medallist (Silver (2022,2021), Bronze (2020)), Singapore Mathematical Olympiad medallist (Bronze (2021,2020), Australian Mathematics Competition High Distinction (2021), International Competitions and Assessments for Schools in Mathematics highest scoring participant (2019)

## OTHER PROJECTS

#### CharacterGuesser (self initiated)

- Developed a telegram bot for playing a game of guessing characters from cropped parts of images (with different modes such as shuffle and blur), receiving 100% positive reviews
- Gained practical experience of telegram bot development with Python and web scraping with Selenium

## **Project Work Word Counter (self initiated)**

- Built a google docs addon to count project work document word count according to H1 Project Work guidelines
- Gained practical experience of google application scripting using Javascript